

MERN STACK DEVELOPER

## **Details**

Flat Num 207 Wing No 2
Rajat SAnkul Opp S.T. Bus Stand
Ganeshpeth Nagpur
Nagpur, 440018
India
7972327621
yash.yadav29@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Indian

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

29/04/1994

Nagpur

#### Links

linkedin

**GitHub** 

Instagram

**Twitter** 

## Skills

Node.js

MySQL

MongoDB

Git

React

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Bootstrap

Tailwind

Firebase

### **Profile**

Driven and determined software engineer, promoting 4.5+ yrs years of experience in building client applications. Offers strong interpersonal and communication skills. I am looking for a place where my skills and expertise is being fully utilized and proved to be an asset to the company. Since last 3 years I am working as a Java full-stack developer.

# **Employment History**

Full Stack Developer, Pickworth Enterprises Pvt. Ltd., Nagpur

APRIL 2021 - PRESENT

- · Worked to assess competing websites in regards to content, look, and feel.
- Worked as a productive and positive team member to design, code, test, report, and debug operations.
- Managed front-end and back-end development in the company's Portfolio Analyst, Employee Track, and Account Management systems.

## Front-End Developer, Pickworth Enterprises Pvt. Ltd., Nagpur

JANUARY 2019 - MARCH 2021

- · Determining the structure and design of web pages.
- · Ensuring user experience determines design choices.
- · Developing features to enhance the user experience.
- · Building reusable code for future use.
- · Optimizing web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- · Utilizing a variety of markup languages to write web pages.

## Intern Trainee, Pickworth Enterprises Pvt. Ltd., Nagpur

JUNE 2018 - DECEMBER 2018

- · Performing clerical duties.
- · Managing social media and emails.
- · Enter data into spreadsheets.

## Education

Civil Engineering, KITS College of Engineering , Nagpur

12th Intermediate, M. B. Convent High School & Junior College, Nagpur

10th High-School, M. B. Convent High School, Nagpur

## Courses

Java Programming, Great Learning

JANUARY 2023

Salesforce Administrator & App Builder, Simplilearn

JANUARY 2023

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials, AWS Training & Certification

FEBRUARY 2023

AWS Technical Essentials, AWS Training & Certification

JANUARY 2023

Redux	
Java	
JavaScript	

#### Hobbies

Team Sport, Travelling, Photography, Singing

## Languages

English

Hindi

Marathi

#### **Projects**

#### Real Estate Website

- Realtor clone built with React js 18, Firebase 9, Tailwind CSS 3, and React router 6.
- . This is a Full stack web application including the Firebase 9 for the back-end.
- · By using this application one can buy, rent & sell their properties.

Technology Used: React js 18, Firebase 9, Tailwind CSS 3, and React router 6.

#### **Gym Exercises App**

- This app is designed to help with exercise, other types of physical training along with the videos.
- This application is fully responsive with mobile also.
- With the functionality to choose exercise categories and specific muscle groups, browse more than one thousand exercises with practical examples, pagination, exercise details, pull related videos from youtube, display similar exercises, and much more.

Technology Used: React 18, Rapid API, HTML, CSS

#### Restaurant Website With Modern UI/Ux

- Built the entire website with up to date technologies and frameworks.
- Work closely with the design team to optimize usability and implement front-end.

Technology Used: ReactJS, Figma, HTML, CSS.

### Al Image Generator App (MERN)

- · This is a DALL-E clone wen application.
- This is artificial intelligence application which can generate everything from memes and art to beautiful UI/UX design.
- A user can also post the image in DALL-E community section which is generated by the AI.

**Technology Used:** Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, React.js, Tailwind CSS, Cloudinary: A cloud based image storage service

### Al Powered T-Shirt Design

- In this website user can change the color of t-shirt and also Add custom color and file support.
- User can Generate and use images through DALLE Al. and also Download the resulting t-shirt model image.
- · This is a fully responsive modern UI/UX design.

Technology Used: React, ThreeJS, Tailwind CSS, React Three Fiber, Framer Motion,